Guide to the Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 5: Boxes 89-110
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 5: Boxes 89-110
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 5: Boxes 89-110
5583/1
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
120 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations. The materials issued by corporations include company histories, employee newsletters, employee benefit plans, personnel practice manuals, performance appraisal forms, affirmative action policies, training brochures, job descriptions, and career development programs as well as national trade association documents and recruitment material.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Several economic activities(sectors) are represented in the collection, such as manufacturing, transportation, mining, banking, insurance, utilities, trade, and services. Corporations whose pamphlets are held in the collection include AT&T, Bethlehem Steel, Bell Telephone System, Firestone Tire & Rubber, Ford Motor Co., General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, General Motors, Goodyear Tire & Rubber, Heinz, International Harvester, Johnson & Johnson, Lockheed Aircraft Co., Maytag Co., Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., National Association of Manufacturers, Pennsylvania Railroad Co., Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Standard Oil, Tennessee Valley Authority, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse Electric among numerous other corporations.
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into six sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-22
Section 2: Boxes 23-44
Section 3: Boxes 45-66
Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Section 5: Boxes 89-110
Section 6: Boxes 111-121
SUBJECTS
Names:
A. Philip Randolph Institute.; Abbott Laboratories.; Abbott Laboratories. House Organs.; Abraham & Straus.; Addressograph-Multigraph Corporation.; Administrative Management Society.; Adult Education Association.; Aero Supply Mfg. Co.; Aerojet-General Corporation.; Aeroquip Corporation.; Aerospace Industries Association of America.; Aetna Life Insurance Company (Hartford, Conn.); Affiliated Schools for Workers.; African- American Labor Center.; Agway Inc.; Air Reduction Company.; Air Transport Association of America.; Airlines Negotiating Committee.; Alaska. Department of Administration.Division of Personnel.; Alden's, Inc.; Alexander Smith & Sons, Carpet Co.; Allegheny Ludlum Steel Corporation.; Allegheny Metal.; Allied Chemical & Dye Corporation; Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company.; Aluminum Company of America.; American Arbitration Association.; American Brake Shoe Company.; American Can Company.; American Labor Education Service.; American Locomotive Company.; American Management Association.; American Merchant Marine Institute.; American Metal Climax, Inc.; American Motors Corporation.; American Petroleum Institute.; American Plan Association.; American Society of Safety Engineers.; American Telephone and Telegraph Company.; American Textile Manufacturers Institute.; American Thread Company.; American Trucking Associations.; American Type Founders Company.; American Vocational Association.; Americans Against Union Control of Government.; Amtrak.; Anaconda American Brass Company.; Anaconda Company.; Anaconda Copper Mining Company.; Anaconda Wire and Cable Company.; Anchor Hocking Glass Corporation.; Armco Steel Corporation.; Armour and Company.; Armstrong Cork Company.; Associated Builders & Contractors (U.S.); Associated General Contractors of America.; Association of American Railroads.; Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad Company.; Atlantic Refining Company.; Atlas Chemical Industries.; ATO, Inc.; Automobile Manufacturers Association.; Automotive and Aviation Parts Manufacturers.; Automotive Council for War Production.; Bell & Howell Co.; Bell Aircraft Corporation.; Bell of Pennsylvania.; Bell Telephone Company.; Bell Telephone Laboratories.; Bethlehem Steel Corporation.; Bird and Son, Inc.; Bituminous Coal Operators' Association.; Bloomer Brothers.; Boeing Aerospace Company.; Boeing Company.; Borden Company.; Brockway Glass Company.; Building Trades Employers' Association.; Bureau of National Affairs (Arlington, Va.); Burlington Industries, Inc.; Burndy Engineering Company.; Burrough Corporation.; California Institute of Technology. Industrial Relations Center.; California Institute of Technology.; California State Personnel Board.; Canadian National Railways; Canadian Pacific Railway Company.; Carborundum Company (Niagara Falls, N.Y.); Carnation Company.; Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation.; Carrier Corporation.; Caterpillar Tractor Company.; Celanese Corporation.; Central Hudson Gas and Electric Corporation.; Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America.; Chemical Corn Exchange Bank.; Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company of Maryland.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company of Virginia.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company.; Chessie System, inc.; Chicago Transit Authority.; Chrysler Corporation.; Cincinnati Bell Inc.; Civil Service Assembly of the United States and Canada.; Climax Molybdenum Company.; Clothing Manufacturers Association of the U.S.A.; Colgate-Palmolive Company.; Colorado Fuel and Iron Company.; Columbia Gas Company.; Commerce and Industry Association of New York.; Committee for the Nation's Health.; Commonwealth Edison Company.; Communications Workers of America.; Cone Mills Corporation.; Connecticut General Life Insurance Company.; Consolidated Edison Company of New York, inc.; Consolidated Gas, Electric Light, and Power Company of Baltimore.; Consolidated Natural Gas Company.; Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation.; Consumers' League of New York City.; Consumers Power Company (Mich.); Container Corporation of America.; Continental Can Company.; Continental Insurance Company.; Continental Oil Company.; Cooperative League of the U.S.A.; Corn Products Refining Company.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.; Cornell University.; Corning Glass Works.; Council Against Communist Aggression (U.S.); Council for International Progress in Management (USA); Council of Profit Sharing Industries (U.S.); Crane Co.; Crane Packing Co.; Credit Union National Association.; Crouse-Hinds Company.; Crown Zellerbach Corporation.; Crucible Steel Company of America.; Dan River Mills Inc.; Dartnell Corporation.; Daystrom, inc.; Dartnell Corporation.; Deere & Company.; Detroit Edison Company.; Diamond Alkali Company.; Dictaphone Corp.; Dole Food Company.; Douglas Aircraft Company.; Dow Chemical Company.; E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Company.; Eagle Pencil Company.; Eastern Gas and Fuel Associates.; Eastern Western & Southwestern Canier Company.; Eastman Kodak Company.; Eaton Corporation.; Eaton Manufacturing Company.; Ecusta Paper Company.; Electronic Industries Alliance.; Eli Lilly and Company.; Employers' Association of Chicago.; Employers' Association of Detroit.; Employers' Association of Grand Rapids.; Employers' Association of Massachusetts.; Employers' Association of Milwaukee.; Employers' Association of Pittsburgh.; Employers' Association of Washington.; Employers' Group of Insurance Companies.; Employers' Labor Relations Information Committee.; Employers' of Mutual of Wasau.; Engineers Joint Council. Engineering Manpower Commission.; Erie Railroad Company.; Erie-Lackawanna Railroad Company.; Erlanger Mills, Inc.; Erwin Cotton Mills.; Esso Research and Engineering Company.; Esso Standard Oil Company.; Exxon Corporation; Falstaff Brewing Corporation; Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America; Federal Professional Association (U.S.); Federal Reserve Bank of New York; Federated Employers of San Francisco; Federated Employers of the Bay Area; Fieldcrest Mills Inc.; William Filene's Sons Co.; Firestone Tire and Rubber Company; First National Bank (Ithaca, N.Y.); First National Bank Maryland; First National Bank of Boston; First National Bank of Chicago; First National Bank of Portland (Portland, Me.); First National Bank of St. Louis; First Pennsylvania Bank, N.A.; First Pennsylvania Banking and Trust Company, Philadelphia.; Fischer and Porter Company; Florida Power & Light Company; Ford Foundation; Ford Motor Company; Foster and Forbes Glass Company; Foundation for Economic Education, inc.; General Dynamics Corporation.; General Electric Company; George Fischer, Ltd.; J.N. Adam & Company.; New Jersey Bell Telephone Company.; New York Chamber of Commerce.; Society for Equitable Assurances on Lives and Survivorships.; South Central Bell.; University of California, Berkeley. Institute of Industrial Relations.; William Filene's Sons Co.; Commonwealth Edison Company; A. Philip Randolph Institute; ATO, Inc.; Aero Supply Mfg. Co.; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
Subjects:
Adult education; Aeronautics; Agricultural industries; Aluminum industry and trade; Airlines; Aircraft industry; Agricultural machinery; Architectural metal-work; Audio equipment industry; Automobile industry and trade; Arbitration, Industrial; Agricultural chemicals industry; Audio equipment industry; Bituminous materials industry; Building trades; Buildings--Environmental engineering; Banks and banking; Breweries; Baked products industry; Business consultants; Clothing trade; Coal mines and mining; Chemical industry; Compressor industry; Clerks (Retail trade); Computer industry; Cereal products; Consumer protection; Container industry; Credit unions; Clay industries; Cement industries; Copper alloys; Dairy products industry; Detergent industry; Executives--Training of; Electric power transmission; Electronics industries; Food industry and trade; Frozen foods and industry; Footwear industry; Fruit trade; Farm produce--Marketing--Government policy; Finance, Public; Glass container industry; Glass manufacture; Gas extraction; Grain trade; Grocery trade; Gasket industry; Human capital; Hydroelectric power plants; Life insurance.; Iron industry and trade; Property insurance.; Casualty insurance.; Instructional materials industry; Health insurance.; Investment banking; Infant formula industry; Knit good industry; Labor unions; Local transit; Luggage industry; Logging; Medical supplies industry; Medicaid; Motor vehicle industry; Metal trade; Meat industry and trade; Military vehicle industry; Medical instruments and apparatus industry; Management; Measuring instruments; Natural gas pipelines; Notions (Merchandise); Newspaper publishing; Navigation equipment industry; National security; Office management; Office equipment and supplies; Petroleum refineries; Photographic industry; Paper folding (Graphic design); Public utilities; Paper products industry; Political participation; Plastics industry and trade; Pharmaceutical industry; Paint industry and trade; Public administration; Public opinion polls; Paper bag industry; Retail trade; Rug and carpet industry; Railroads; Rubber industry and trade; Railroad equipment industry; Roller bearings; Security systems industry; Service industries; Social security; Shipment of goods; Sanitary supply industry; Soybean industry; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses; Transportation equipment industry.; Telecommunication.; Trucking industry.; Trucks--Design and construction.; Textile industry.; Trade associations.; Tobacco industry.; Universities and colleges.; Vocational education.; Wood products.; Welding equipment industry.; Woolen goods industry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents); Publications (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this Collection:
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 1: Boxes 1-22
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 2: Boxes 23-44
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 3: Boxes 45-66 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 4: Boxes 67-88
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 6: Boxes 111-121
Related Collections:
5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents
5583/2: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3
5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications
5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5
5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6
5956: Archives Organization File Additional records
CONTAINER LIST
- Box: 89, Folder: 1 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Religious Ideals in Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 89, Folder 1)
    By William Cardinal O'Connell. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Pastoral Letter, Publication (Box 89, Folder 1)
    By National Catholic Welfare Council. September, 1919. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The American Labor Movement, Publication (Box 89, Folder 1)
    By Francis J. HAAS. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: A Catechism of the Social Question, Publication (Box 89, Folder 1)
    By John Ryan. March 2, 1921. Item is in English.
- Box: 89, Folder: 2 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: NCDS Services to Campus Communities, Publication (Box 89, Folder 2)
    By Alfred E. Cowles. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: NCDS Services in the Housing Field, Publication (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: NCDS Police Training Programs, Publication (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: NCDS Consumer Programs, Publication (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: NCDS Services to Health Care Programs, Publication (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Publication (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: News From the National Center for Dispute Settlement of the American Arbitration Association, Publication (Box 89, Folder 2)
    September 1972. Item is in English.
- Box: 89, Folder: 3 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: A Plant-Wide Productivity Plan in Action: Three Years of Experience with the Scanlon Plan, Publication (Box 89, Folder 3)
    By National Center for Productivity and Quality Working Life. May 1975. Item is in English.
- Box: 89, Folder: 4 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: America's Choice: high skills or low wages!, Publication (Box 89, Folder 4)
    By National Center on Education and the Economy. Item is in English.
- Box: 89, Folder: 5 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Before the Joint Committee on Government and Finance West Virginia Legislature, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
    By National Coal Association. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Coal Age, Coal Week and AMR Conference on Coal Energy, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Coal, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Coal and Research, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Coal in Today's World, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: Coal and the Environment, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: map of Coal Areas in the United States, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: The 1920 Soft Coal Shortage, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 9: More Capital Equipment Coal's Foremost Economic Need, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
    By Donald R.G. Cowan. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Royalty Funds to Labor Unions Should be Nipped in the Bud!, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 11: Labor Union Monopolies and the anti-trust laws, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 12: The Bituminous Coal Industry Its Contract with the United Mine Workers and the National Interest, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 13: Transportation the Problem of soft Coal, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 14: Statement of J.C. Brydon, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 15: Why the Coal Industry Opposes Government Promotion of Hydro Power, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 16: The Coal Industry and the Government's Hydro Electric Plants, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
    By E. A. Holbrook. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Amply Financed and Already Under Way, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 18: Report of the U.S. Coal Commission on the Anthracite Industry, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
    By H. A. Mills. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: Coal--The Abundant Alternative, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
    By Carl E. Bagge. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: Coal: The Once and Future King, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 21: Coal and the U.S. Government: A Love- Hate Relationship, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 22: Proposed Amendments to Erisa Regarding Multiemployer Pension Plans, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 23: The Lessons of the First Year of the 1978 Wage Agreement, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 24: Statement by Joseph P. Brennan, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 25: HR 3904 Amendments to Title IV of ERISA Multiemployer Pension Plans, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 26: Address by Joseph P. Brennan, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 27: Before the tenth Annual Institute on Coal Mining Health, Safety and Research, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 28: Before the Pittsburgh Coal Mining Institute of America Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Item 29: Before the Committee on Public Works, Publication (Box 89, Folder 5)
- Box: 89, Folder: 6 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Government Takes Over Two Coal Companies - Foremen Strikes Back, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. Bulletin No. 2255. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Coal Production and Demand, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2249. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: WPB Determines "Order of Preference" in the Rationing of Truck and Bus Tires, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2250-A. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Stocks, Consumption, and Days' Supply of Bituminous Coal, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2251. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Senate Rejects Kilgore-Murray Bill: Approves George Bill Amending Social Security Act, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. 2252. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: In Congress This Past Week: Surplus Property Disposal - Demobilization - and Unemployment Insurance Questions, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2253. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Foremen and Supervisory Forces Strike at Mines of Two Companies in Pennsylvania, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2254. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Southern Coal Producers Association Signs Wage Contract, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2244. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: NCA Board Met at Cleveland June 21, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2245-A. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Jewell Ridge Portal-to-Portal Appeal Submitted to Court, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2246. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Special Selective Service Bulletin, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2247. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Manpower Commission Promises to Help Recruit Miners, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2248. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Comments on Production, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2243. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Coal Stocks as of May 1, 1944, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2242. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Supreme Court Denies Certiorari in Jewell Ridge Portal-to-Portal Case, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2241. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: Operators and CMA Officials Confer Looking To Early Return o The Mines to Their Owners, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2240. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: War Labor Board Gives Its Approval to Coal Wage Contract Between United Mine Workers and Large Number of Operators As Submitted to WLB December 17, 1943: The Vote was 10-2, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2239-A. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: N.C.A. Executive Committee Met at New York May 10, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2238. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: NWLB Reported Reaching Decision on Wage Contract, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2237. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: Mine Manpower, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2236. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: Conference Here on UMWA Demand for $40 Travel Time Payment: No Conclusion Reached, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2235. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: Mine Manpower and the Question of Draft Deferment, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2234. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: Ickes Opposes Further Drafting of Coal Miners and Warns of Consequences; Operators Point to Need for 40,000 Additional Miners, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2233. Item is in English.
  - Item 24: Supreme Court 7 to 2 Decision, Holds Underground Travel is Time Worked in Ore Mining, United Mine Workers Perfects Its Appeal to U.S. Circuit Court in Jewell Ridge Case, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2232. Item is in English.
  - Item 25: No Coupon Rationing of Coal Next Winter, WPB's Decision, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2231. Item is in English.
  - Item 26: Concerning the Present Position of the Coal Mines Administration With Respect to Instruments of Certification and Agreement, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2229. Item is in English.
  - Item 27: 40 Cent Hourly Minimum Wage in Coal Industry Effective March 20, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2228. Item is in English.
  - Item 28: Let's Be Sure We Keep the Home Fires Burning - First, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. No. 2256. Item is in English.
  - Item 29: Hearings Begin In Important Memphis Natural Gas Case, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. Monday, September 11, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 30: Our Mines Should Now Their 1945-1946 Equipment Requirements, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. Saturday, September 16, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 31: N.C.A. Board of Directors to Meet October 25 in New York City, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. Saturday, September 23, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 32: Injunction Proceedings Instituted by Group of Southern Coal Companies, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. Tuesday, September 26, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 33: Production of Bituminous Coal for the Week Ended Sept. 23 - 11,650,000 Net Tons, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. Saturday, September 30, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 34: Appellate Court Reverses Lower Court Decision in Jewell Ridge Portal-to-Portal Case, Publication (Box 89, Folder 6)
    By National Coal Association. Saturday, October 7, 1944. Item is in English.